Guide to the Asia Pacific Forum Records TAM 629
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Asia Pacific Forum Records
1997-2010
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
TAM 629
4 Linear Feet in 4 records boxes
Asia Pacific Forum (APF), founded by a collective of journalists and political activists, is a weekly pan-Asian radio show based in New York City that began in broadcasting 1998 on 99.5 WBAI, a non-commercial and listener-sponsored radio station. The program covers stories from Asia and on Asian American communities and individuals, focusing on culture and politics. Its records document approximately 500 of APF's on-air shows between 1998-2009, in scripts, research notes, electronic records of e-mail messages posted to the APF's internal listserv and public e-mail list, audio cassette tapes, reel-to-reel audio tapes, compact discs, mini-discs, VHS tapes and DVDs. Among the audio recordings are airchecks for some of the shows, as well as full-length unedited recorded interviews with notable Asian Americans. An archived link to APF's website provides a connection to complete APF broadcasts from August 2006 forward.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Leyla Mei on behalf of the Asia Pacific Forum in 2014. The accession number associated with this gift is 2013.001.
Appraisal
No materials were separated from this collection.
Arrangement
Arranged into seven series. In most cases original folder and audio tape titles have been retained. Series I and IV, and are arranged chronologically; Series II and III have been arranged in alphabetical order. Series V and VI are unprocessed and have not been arranged by archivist.
Missing Title
Asia Pacific Forum Scripts and Background and Research Materials
Asia Pacific Forum - Administrative
WBAI - Pacifica
Reel to Reel Audio Tapes
Unprocessed Audio Cassette Tapes, Mini Discs, DIgital Data Tape (DAT), Videotapes and DVDs
Unprocessed Compact Discs
Asia Pacific Forum Archived Website
Historical/Biographical Note
Asia Pacific Forum (APF) is a weekly pan-Asian radio show based in New York City that broadcasts on WBAI 99.5 and streams live on the Internet. Focusing on culture and politics, APF's broadcasts cover underreported stories from Asia and on Asian American communities and individuals, exploring topics including social and political movements, civil and human rights, foreign policy, immigration, history, labor, literature, pop culture, and the performing arts. WBAI is part of the Pacifica Foundation, a non-commercial and listener-sponsored national radio network.
APF was founded in 1998, when Samori Marksman, program director of WBAI, and Sybil Wong, former business director of WBAI, brought together a group of journalists and progressive political activists to organize a weekly program focused on New York's Asian communities. Founding members included Kil Huh, John Kim, Jungwon Kim, Suen-yi Meng, and Doualy Xaykaotao. APF was organized as a collective and has continued to operate as one. A formal application process to join the collective was instituted in 2005. As of 2011, core collective members included Amna Akbar, Vivek Bharathan, Michelle Chen, Andrew Hsiao, Hyun Lee, Leyla Mei, Dorian Merina, Silky Shah, Naureen Shah, and Irene Tung.
Soon after the founding of APF, the show began a partnership with SAMAR magazine, the South Asian Magazine for Action and Reflection, a New York-based publication that explores the politics and culture of South Asia and the South Asian diaspora. During this time, members of the SAMAR collective, including Ananya Bhattacharjee, Aniruddha Das, Satinder Jawanda, Chandana Mathur, S. Shankar, and others, produced and hosted one show per month. The arrangement ended in 2001, when several SAMAR members joined the APF collective. APF quickly expanded its coverage to encompass East Asia, South Asia, Southeast Asia, the Middle East, and the Pacific as well as Asian America.
The show's content is local, national, and international in scope. Among the Asian and Asian American newsmakers that have been featured on APF are Arundhati Roy, Tariq Ali, David Henry Hwang, Monique Truong, Edward Said, Maxine Hong Kingston, Vijay Prashad, Cathi Tactaquin, Grace Lee Boggs, Bhairavi Desai, Lois-Ann Yamanaka, Margaret Fung, Mike Honda, John Liu, Stacey Ann Chin, Jeff Chang, and DJ Rekha. In 2006, APF began podcasting and making its weekly broadcasts available as downloads on the Web, allowing the show to reach a broader audience both nationally and globally.
Custodial History
The archived website was migrated from the California Digital Library's Web Archiving Service to the Internet Archive's Archive-It Service in November 2015. The link to California Digital Library was removed in October 2017.
Scope and Content Note
The Asia Pacific Forum Records document approximately 500 of APF's on-air shows from 1998-2009, including scripts (some annotated with hand-written notes), preparatory materials, and research notes for shows (including biographies of guests and background articles), along with some documentation of APF's publicity efforts. In addition there are electronic records (mainly stored on compact discs) consisting of e-mail messages posted to the collective's internal listserv and discussion board, as well as its public e-mail list. A significant portion of the records also include audio cassette tapes, compact discs, mini-discs, and reel-to-reel audio tapes. Some of these materials contain airchecks (complete recordings of APF's live broadcasts, recorded in the studio by the host(s) of these shows). Of particular significance among the collection's audio recordings are full-length unedited recorded interviews with notable Asian Americans including activist Yuri Kochiyama, novelist Jessica Hagedorn, and musician and activist Chris Iijima. A small part of the records consist of VHS tapes and DVDs sent to APF by outside producers or distributors for promotional purposes or for consideration for possible inclusion in its programs. In addition, an archived link to APF's website makes it possible to directly listen to APF broadcasts from August 2006 forward. The collection does not contain a complete set of recordings of all of APF's shows, nor does it include a comprehensive list of all of APF's broadcasts (at present no such document exists) or any transcripts for the shows.
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Access to audiovisual materials in this collection is available through digitized access copies. Researchers may view an item's original container, but the media themselves are not available for playback because of preservation concerns. Materials that have already been digitized are noted in the collection's finding aid and can be requested in our reading room. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. Other parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes Javascript, streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Full-Text searches of archived websites are available at https://archive-it.org/organizations/567.
Bibiliography
Most of the information for this guide was drawn from an historical sketch written by Andrew Hsiao and Leyla Mei, Asia Pacific Forum Collective members, that was cited in the description of the records on the webpage for the Asian/Pacific American Documentary Heritage Archives Survey. The Asian/Pacific American Documentary Heritage Archives Survey was a joint project of the Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Archives and the Asian/Pacific/American Institute, both of New York University, carried out in 2011.
Asia Pacific Forum Records. Accessed October 10, 2014. http://dev-dl-pa.home.nyu.edu/tamimentapa/?q=node/209
Asian Americans and mass media; Asian Americans.; Asian Americans -- Social conditions.; Asia Pacific Forum; Mei, Leyla
- Series I: Asia Pacific Forum Scripts and Background and Research Materials
  Scope and Content Note
  Includes folders for specific shows and topics as well as folders that contain materials for several different shows and topics.
  - APF Scripts Etc., 1998-1999 (Box 1)
  - APF Human Rights Watch: "We Are Not the Enemy", ca 2000 (Box 1)
  - SAMAR/WBAI Radio Scripts, 2000 (Box 1)
  - Dams, ca April-November 2000 (Box 1)
  - APF Scripts Etc., 2001 (Box 1)
  - APF Aceh; No to Cogentrix; Tong Zhi Comrade - Out in Asian America, April 2001 (Box 1)
  - Hindu Right/Jewish Right, ca August 2001 (Box 1)
  - APF [Program], March 27, 2002 (Box 1)
  - APF: Bhopal, New Developments; Barbara Tran, September 17, 2002 (Box 1)
  - APF Pakistan Elections/Patsy Mink's Progressive Legacy/Anand Patwardhan Films, November 5, 2002 (Box 1)
  - IDRF: Foreign Funding of Hate, November 2002 (Box 1)
  - APF Bd Journalists Arrested/U.S.-South Korea Relations/NY Freedom Conference, December 3, 2002 (Box 1)
  - APF Meema Seshu/Riverside Church, December 24, 2002 (Box 1)
  - APF Bonded Child Labor in Silk Industry/U.N. Inspector/Brecht Panel, January 28, 2003 (Box 1)
  - Arundhati Roy & Enron, ca January-March 2003 (Box 1)
  - Iraq War, March-April 2003 (Box 1)
  - APF [Programs], June-August 2003 (Box 1)
  - APF [Programs], September, November 2003 (Box 1)
  - APF Food, December 3, 2003 (Box 1)
  - APF 2003 (Box 1)
  - APF [Programs], 2004 (Box 1)
  - APF Congressman Mike Honda; World Social Forum, January 13, 2004 (Box 1)
  - APF Hindu Right/UK; Asian American Writers Workshop; Queer Asian Pacific Conference, March 2, 2004 (Box 1)
  - APF James Yee [Guantanamo]; South Korea [President's Impeachment]; Exhibit "Paradise Now", March 30, 2004 (Box 1)
  - APF Charlie Chan, April 13, 2004 (Box 1)
  - APF Reagan, G8, Human Rights Film Festival, June 8, 2004 (Box 1)
  - APF Mark Dow; James Yee's Parents; Teabag Open Mic, June 24, 2004 (Box 1)
  - APF Dick Cheney, August 31, 2004 (Box 1)
  - Hagedorn, October 5, 2004 (Box 1)
  - APF Voting; Asian American Conservatives, October 19, 2004 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous Scripts, Background and Research Materials, 2003-2005 (Box 1)
  - APF Tsumani Aid Effort; Han Ong, January 5, 2005 (Box 2)
  - Phillippines; Epidemics; Harley Spiller, April 19, 2005 (Box 2)
  - APF Real I.D. Act; Nepal; Taxi!, May 10, 2005 (Box 2)
  - APF Tariq Ali; Tahrir, May 24, 2005 (Box 2)
  - APF Chinese Labor and American Consumerism at the Human Rights Watch Film Festival; Arms Deal Between Israel and China; Anita Dube, June 7, 2005 (Box 2)
  - APF Fletcher/SEIU, June 21, 2005 (Box 2)
  - APF Iraq War Tribunal, July 19, 2005 (Box 2)
  - APF Bangladesh; AAJA, August 23, 2005 (Box 2)
  - APF P. Kwong; Torture, November 15, 2005 (Box 2)
  - APF [Programs], 2005 (Box 2)
  - APF Chris Iijima; Five Streams, January 17, 2006 (Box 2)
  - APF HR 4437; Thailand; Yamanaka, March 28, 2006 (Box 2)
  - APF Golden Venture (Film About); Immigration; Kwong on Hu Jintao, April 25, 2006 (Box 2)
  - APF Affirmative Action; "Return to Sender'; Mike Kang's [Film] "Motel", June 27, 2006 (Box 2)
  - APF Domestic Workers; Red Doors (Film), September 5, 2006 (Box 2)
  - APF Aziz Huq (Military Commission Act); Thailand (Voice Against Coup); Literature from the "Axis of Evil", October 3, 2006 (Box 2)
  - APF Moazzam Begg (Former Guantanamo Detainee), October 17, 2006 (Box 2)
  - APF Korea; Pakistan; Bangladesh; "One Way or Another", November 21, 2006 (Box 2)
  - APF KAPOW! ABC's Gene Yang; Ellen Young, January 2, 2007 (Box 2)
  - APF U.S.-India Nuclear Deal; Immigration; Oshiro on Dorothea Lange Internment Images, January 9, 2007 (Box 2)
  - APF Deepa Frenandes; Migrants in Korea; Kenneth Lee, March 6, 2007 (Box 2)
  - APF Vijay Prasad; Ahish Nandi; Saigon Grill, March 27, 2007 (Box 2)
  - APF South Asian Art; Sukhder Sandhu; Mohammed Ali; SAWCC, April 17, 2007 (Box 2)
  - APF Pakistan; NAAATF; Stone Forest Ensemble, June 12, 2007 (Box 2)
  - APF U.S. Social Forum; Race and Schools; Challenging China (Opposition Voices), July 3, 2007 (Box 2)
  - APF Okazaki; Hiroshima; Race and Restaurants (Saru Jayaraman), August 7, 2007 (Box 2)
  - APF Pakistan; Japan; "Intifada New York City", August 14, 2007 (Box 2)
  - APF U.S.-India Nuclear Deal; Queer Korea, September 4, 2007 (Box 2)
  - APF LSFH; Klare; Nina Revoger, April 8, 2008 (Box 2)
  - APF Global Food Crisis; China's Outcasts; Hollywood Chinese (documentary film), April 29, 2008 (Box 2)
  - APF Obama/McCain on Immigration; Renku Sen, October 14, 2008 (Box 2)
  - APF Chalmers Johnson; Ed Park, October 21, 2008 (Box 2)
  - APF Queer China; Karan Mahajan, November 25, 2008 (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous Research Materials, 1997-2010 (Box 2)
  - APF Scripts - Undated (Box 2)
- Series II: Asia Pacific Forum - Administrative
  Includes a list of APF's early programs and a small amount of organizational materials for APF.
  - APA Collective's Lists of Its Members/APA Contact List, undated (Box 2)
  - Grants, undated (Box 2)
  - Lists of Titles and Descriptions For Programs From 1997-2001, undated (Box 2)
  - Minutes of APA Collective Meeting; Correspondence; Internal Correspondence; Notes; Program Ideas; Promotional Materials, 1995-2010; undated (Box 2)
- Series III: WBAI - Pacifica
  Historical/Biographical Note
  WBAI is part of the Pacifica Foundation, a non-commercial and listener-sponsored national radio network founded in 1946, with circa 50 affiliates including stations in New York, Los Angeles, Berkeley, Washington, D.C., Berkeley and Houston, and other cities across the United States.
  Includes documents pertaining to fundraising for WBAI and for Asia Pacific Forum programs and internal turmoil at the radio station and the Pacifica Foundation.
  - Pacifica Crisis (2000) (Box 2)
  - Program Council, 2003-2004 (Box 2)
  - Membership Drives/Fundraisers, undated (Box 2)
- Series IV: Reel to Reel Audio Tapes
  Eighteen reel to reel tapes (and one empty labeled reel to reel tape box); seven 10" reels; eleven 10" reels
  - Five-Hour Special on Asian Americans – Part 1 of 6 (Introduction/Overview), May 6, 1998 (Box 4)
  - Asian Americans Entering the Challenge of the 21rst Century – Part 3 of 6 – (Economy/Economic Status) Host: Phil Tajitsu Nash, Guest: Thea Lea, May 6, 1998
  - Asian Americans Entering the Challenge of the 21rst Century – Segment 6, May 6, 1998 (Box 4)
  - NAPAWF Interview Backup [empty box], September 14, 1998 (Box 4)
  - Tibet Arts, October 3, 1998 (Box 4)
  - Tibet International Support, October 3, 1998 (Box 4)
  - APF Labor Program [?] September 1, 1999? (Box 4)
  - Fil-Am Writers, 1999 (Box 4)
  - Ron Takaki … (on "Double Victory – A Multicultural History of America in World War II) 23.30 Broadcast June 14, 2000 (Box 4)
  - APF – AAIFF 7/28 Head Out, undated (Box 4)
  - Banned Books [?], undated
  - Chaumtoli [?]/Andrew K. Workers Rights Clinic, undated (Box 4)
  - Clip 1 – Nixon; Clip 2 Ford, undated (Box 4)
  - [Illegible] 2 of 2, undated (Box 4)
  - Master Lin Dong – Body of Jade Qigong, undated
  - My Tost [?] [TGST?], undated (Box 4)
  - Unlabeled, undated (Box 4)
  - Unlabeled, undated (Box 4)
- Series V: Unprocessed Audio Cassette Tapes, Mini Discs, Digital Data Tape (DAT), Videotapes and DVDs, ca 2000-2007 (Box 3)
  Mini-discs include Asia Pacific Forum interviews, airchecks, programs and unedited programs dated 03/10/2003; 07/22/2003; 08/12/2003; 11/2003; 12/03/2003;06/08/2004; 06/29/2004 07/27/2004; 09/28/2004; 10/19/2004; 12/07/2004; 01/04/2005; 03/29/2005; 06/20/2005; 07/03/2005; 08/18/2005; 11/11/2005; 12/20/2005; 12/22/2006; 06/11/2007; 12/03/2007; also undated disks.
  Audio cassette tapes labeled as follows: APF Asian-American Conservatives August 2, 2000; APF "Chinatown Files" Two Excerpts, April 22, 2001; Flower Drum Song, November Elections November 12, 2002; APF February 4, 2003 Show; APF Aircheck November 11, 2003; APF Hagedorn/Wienfield April 13, 2004; APA Teach-in/North Korea and Beyond April 23, 2003; APF April 29, 2003; APF Singh/Non-Citizens September 2, 2003; APF Healthcare & BCIS/Reparations December 30, 2003; Forbidden City undated; Ron Takaki Interview.
  One DAT labeled: APF Spring Marathon [Program], May 17, 2000
  Video materials consist of what seem to be review copies submitted to, or acquired by, APF. These include nine VHS, with seven titles distributed by Asian Cinevision ("Septet," "AV," "62 Years and 6,500 Miles Between," "Shape of the Moon,"and "Sleeping Tigers: The Asahi Baseball Story"), and two others "Rewind – By Hak-Soon Kim," and "Pacific Rim News Review – 6/10/04 – S.J. Gluck; Recession in China?", and three DVDs labeled "White Light/Black Rain Clip Reel (12/26/2006),"Hollywood Chinese," "Killer Coke," "Manufactured Landscapes (2006)."
- Series VI: Unprocessed Compact Discs, 2001-2010 (Box 3)
  There are approximately 400 items. Contents of the files contained in these items include audio (APF programs--some completed, some unedited, music, interviews) and text (notes, research materials, and scripts).
- Series VII: Asia Pacific Forum Archived Website, Sep 21, 2014-ongoing
  In 2006, APF began podcasting and making its weekly broadcasts available as downloads on its website, allowing the show to reach a broader audience both nationally and globally. The APF website also has listings for music played on the program, book recommendations, news, and events.